<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://jacknight-and-friends.vercel.app/</id>
    <title>Jacknight's Blog</title>
    <updated>2025-05-21T13:21:54.347Z</updated>
    <generator>Feed for Node.js</generator>
    <author>
        <name>Jacknight</name>
        <email>wang.jiankai@outlook.com</email>
        <uri>https://jacknight-and-friends.vercel.app/</uri>
    </author>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://jacknight-and-friends.vercel.app/"/>
    <link rel="self" href="https://jacknight-and-friends.vercel.app//atom.xml"/>
    <subtitle>Articles on web development, technology, and more</subtitle>
    <logo>https://jacknight-and-friends.vercel.app//favicon.png</logo>
    <icon>https://jacknight-and-friends.vercel.app//favicon.ico</icon>
    <rights>All rights reserved 2025, Jacknight</rights>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jacknight Weekly 01]]></title>
        <id>https://jacknight-and-friends.vercel.app//blog/jacknight-weekly-01</id>
        <link href="https://jacknight-and-friends.vercel.app//blog/jacknight-weekly-01"/>
        <updated>2025-05-20T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As a part of a new series, I&#39;ll try to piece together my recent readings and findings. Some of which are pieces that I&#39;ve heard brillient people talking that makes me reflect deeper into myself. I&#39;ll post them here, for my personal reminder, also for your encouragement.</p>
<p>Need to mention, some or most of them are just opinions, not facts. There&#39;s no certain path to follow, if it does exist, follow what leads your heart.</p>
<h2>Keep the momentum.</h2>
<p>This was brought up in a social event after weeks of exams. By context, it refers to the fact that one shouldn&#39;t let go of the state of mental fulfillness and keep things undergoing. Personally, I think it&#39;s also about building a life cycle with consistent dedication to tasks and focus that runs automatically. Conversively, eating cold served food, may not be a good ieda.</p>
<h2>Two way doors.</h2>
<p>It&#39;s one of Amazon&#39;s Leadership Principles that some of us shared concensus. It basically refers a situation where one&#39;s stuck with the decision whether to move forward and being indecisive. By two way doors, it means always trying the other option when there is. If it fails, just naturally falls back to where one left off. </p>
<p>I recalled this not because it&#39;s anything new, but mostly as a reminder for myself that I should at least try options before landing myself in any position, comfortable or not. And that this idea of evolution should be embedded in our daily process.</p>
<h2>Keep chasing novelty with performance</h2>
<p>The thing is it&#39;s way easier to get stuck in a field, only worrying about what&#39;s happening around. One can be a excellent fish hunter after generations of hunting in the north Atalantic, yet he&#39;s never had any experience of riding camels in a desert. Life is not just about persuing absolute excellence in one area, but also in the joy of discovering diverse experience in the vast world. Trying new combinations may somehow lead to unexpected results.</p>
<p>Nolvelty is a sense of interestingness increment. Go explore the unknown part of the chart my friend.</p>
<p>To conclude, there&#39;re some pictures taken recently at the Seven Sisters Cliff. Nicely weather, calming views, friendly neighbourhood, curious seegulls (trying to share our fish &amp; chips). If anyone&#39;s interested in going to Briton, you should try this place named Pinocchio, they&#39;ve got the best Italian food(Personally).
<img src="https://site-resources.lon1.cdn.digitaloceanspaces.com/images/posts/weekly1/cliff1.jog" alt="Seven Sisters Cliff">
<img src="https://site-resources.lon1.cdn.digitaloceanspaces.com/images/posts/weekly1/cliff2.jpg" alt="Seven Sisters Cliff 2">
<img src="https://site-resources.lon1.cdn.digitaloceanspaces.com/images/posts/weekly1/beach1.jpg" alt="Seaford Beach">
<img src="https://site-resources.lon1.cdn.digitaloceanspaces.com/images/posts/weekly1/beach2.jpg" alt="Seaford Beach 2"></p>
]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Jacknight</name>
            <email>wang.jiankai@outlook.com</email>
            <uri>https://jacknight-and-friends.vercel.app/</uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intros]]></title>
        <id>https://jacknight-and-friends.vercel.app//blog/intro</id>
        <link href="https://jacknight-and-friends.vercel.app//blog/intro"/>
        <updated>2025-03-29T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An introduction to my blog]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>A Brief Intro</h3>
<p>I have been longing for this blog for quite some time. It is not until the emergence of AI tools and some undertaken software development experience that makes this possible.</p>
<p>Sometimes you will have this feeling that some ideas have to get out, whether it&#39;s in the shower or some small talks with friends, and it is quite a pity that without recording, they&#39;re very easy to flee away. </p>
<p>In the days to come, I will keep updating this blog with my best ability, to capture these ideas. Hopefully, my readers, you can find this journey worthwhile.</p>
<p>You&#39;re always welcome to drop me an <a href="mailto:wang.jiankai@outlook.com">email</a>.</p>
<h3>About the Main Page Images</h3>
<p>The moss picture was taken on my last journey to Saihoji Garden in August 2024. It was a secret trip meant to get away from the normal life. All efforts paid off when reaching the temple. The tranquility and zen are beyond words.</p>
<p>You see the nature, you see the nurturance, you see momentum.</p>
<p>You discover deeper in yourself.</p>
<p><img src="https://site-resources.lon1.cdn.digitaloceanspaces.com/images/saihoji-monk.JPG" alt="saihoji monk| photographed in Aug,2024">
<img src="https://site-resources.lon1.cdn.digitaloceanspaces.com/images/saihoji-garden.jpg" alt="saihoji moss garden| photographed in Aug,2024"></p>
]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Jacknight</name>
            <email>wang.jiankai@outlook.com</email>
            <uri>https://jacknight-and-friends.vercel.app/</uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Early Thoughts of Orion]]></title>
        <id>https://jacknight-and-friends.vercel.app//blog/early-thoughts-of-orion</id>
        <link href="https://jacknight-and-friends.vercel.app//blog/early-thoughts-of-orion"/>
        <updated>2024-09-28T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Why Orion should look like this, and why I think it’s a correct way of thinking.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Orion发布后有一些感触，简单谈谈对于Meta产品设计理念的看法，Vision Pro产品定位的一些问题和我对于AR眼镜产品形态的理解。</p>
<p><img src="https://site-resources.lon1.cdn.digitaloceanspaces.com/images/posts/orion/Orion-on-face.png" alt="Glasses, neural wristband and compute puck. Image from The Verge"></p>
<p>Orion采用分体式有几个我认为的原因，一个Meta的芯片设计功力没Apple强，能耗比做不上去，像Vision Pro那样的高ppi双屏显示算力不足会严重影响刷新率。Meta在这方面的自我定位一直很好，年前的Meta Rayban就是很好的例子：他们只保留了摄像头和语音模组，去掉了所有的显示，使之成为了一个很好的第一人称视角眼镜。Meta知道在功能间取舍，我的目标就是做好当前算力范围下的最优体验，不是硬堆算力和散热去让整个产品臃肿化。这种思想也根植在iPhone对于直屏的坚持中，你不得不承认</p>
<p>「有时候优秀的简单设计比稀碎的复杂设计更好」。</p>
<p><img src="https://site-resources.lon1.cdn.digitaloceanspaces.com/images/posts/orion/Vision-Pro.png" alt="Vision Pro, image by Apple"></p>
<p><img src="https://site-resources.lon1.cdn.digitaloceanspaces.com/images/posts/orion/Ray-Ban.png" alt="Meta-Rayban, image by The Verge"></p>
<p>而分体式可以让显示设备，即眼镜本体只专注于成像和通信，计算负荷、发热、功耗都会小很多，技术的可行性更强。这不是主要的，Apple早年在Vision Pro开发的时候也考虑过这个问题，Rockwell他们也做了一个分体式的原型，但是Ive当时给出的解释是希望可以摆脱计算中枢的束缚，能够在空间中自由移动。这个观点不无道理，但是其实像AirPods其实已经给了我们答案：</p>
<p>我们只要把计算中枢小型化到能放进口袋就行了。</p>
<p>放进口袋的分体式设备就是最佳的AR眼睛形态，你既不丧失设备的灵活性，又能够降低头部负荷，一举两得。</p>
<p>然而新的问题诞生了，口袋计算设备一散热package不够大，第二不好做主动散热，这对计算单元的能耗比提出了更高的要求，但是终归来讲相比于Vision Pro目前的集成式迭代路线，显然更具备技术可行性。</p>
<p>（计算单元的电池问题倒是很简单，采用背靠背的磁吸或触点充电形态，不够了换一块就行了，真正的难点还在overall package和ventilation）</p>
<p>Meta在这次的Orion中能真正让人看到他们对于产品定位的理解：</p>
<p>「我不需要那么高清的显示，相反在以现实透视画面为主的增强信息流上用摄像头辅助AI识别分析给出结果/建议，这才是人们想要的」</p>
<p>人们不需要一个可以带着走的电影院，人们出门真的带把伞就足够了。</p>
]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Jacknight</name>
            <email>wang.jiankai@outlook.com</email>
            <uri>https://jacknight-and-friends.vercel.app/</uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>